MANEL DJEHICHE

Javascript Developer | Data Scientist

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Bab Ezzouar Algiers, 16042 Algeria

PHONE

+213 0552230871

EMAIL

maneldje81@gmail.com

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

25-09-1997 Algiers

DRIVING LICENSE

Yes

NATIONALITY

Algerian

LINKS

<u>Linkdin</u>

Github Projects

SKILLS

PHP

CSS

HTML5

SQL

jQuery

PROFILE

I am principally a JavaScript Web Developer with 5 years of experience and a Data Scientist using python with 3 years of experience, I worked with many other technologies like Java, C++, and PHP.

For web development, I am a back-end and front-end programmer using NodeJs and ReactJs having the knowledge to choose the best conception of the database [relational or no relational].

Speaking about Artificial intelligence, I have a good level in Deep learning, NIp, Machine learning, problem resolution, problem optimization, and data mining. I can do data collection and data cleaning, and then build models that help you taking the right decision.

I have worked in many companies which allows me to get strong expertise in team-working, social intelligence, problem resolution, how to discuss the functionalities with the customer, reporting, and choosing the best technologies in order to get the best results possible.

My latest job is as a full stack web developer in Sonelgaz company, it's an international Algerian company that is responsible for sharing the electricity and the gas in all the country, that gave me a good experience in graphs and how to treat complicated problems with high complexity.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full stack web developer, Dz-Canada [Remote - CD]

Québec

Jul 2018 — Dec 2018

- · Creation of dynamic web application using PHP, MySQL,
- Customizing HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP AND REACT templates depending the the need of the client.
- · Building E-commerce websites using OpenCART.

Full Stack Javascript Developer, LAKKINI [CD]

Algeria

Apr 2021 — Nov 2022

• I used to create Restful API using Nodejs, MongoDB on the server-side.

Deep Learning and Machine Learning Conflict Resolution developer, Freelance tasks Apr 2020 — Present React I used to take projects in AI using machine learning and deep learning JavaScript tools. **Typescript** · Data collection using web scraping from websites. · Cleaning data and preparing it for machine learning. AJAX · Creating smart models with TensorFlow, Sklearn, Pandas, and Keras Libraries with Python. **Postgres** Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas and Javascript Web developer, Elit Sonelgaz [CI] SKlearn Dec 2021 — Present Golang 1- Handling graphs and high complexity networks. 2- Real problem resolution and optimization. 3- Back-end using NodeJs and python. LANGUAGES 4- Front-end using ReactJs.

MySQL

Git

Python

Node.is

English

French

Arabic

HTML & CSS

Java

MongoDB

EDUCATION

Master 2 in Artificial Intelligence, University of Science and Technology Houari Boumediene

· On the client-side using REACT, HTML, CSS.

· I used to create GraphQL API using Golang, Postgres.

· Handling microservices architecture and how to define multiple

Microservices with Golang & React-

Jun 2022 — Dec 2022

services.

developer, Emplorium [Remote - CD]

· On the client-side, working with React.

Algiers

Algiers

London

Sep 2018 — Jun 2020

I have got huge expertise in Artificial intelligence from my university in different domains, including data mining, vision computer, NLP, problem resolution, algorithm optimization, and complexity.

Licence in computer systems, University of Algiers algiers

Sep 2015 — Jun 2018

I have learned many things related to web development and database structure, including MySQL database, UML for conception, How to choose the best architecture for database related to the problem, web application, understanding very well how processors and pcs work which allows me to know what data structure to choose in my programs and algorithm.

INTERNSHIPS

Deep Learning Researcher, RESEARCH CENTRE FOR SCIENTIFIC AND TECHNICAL INFORMATION

Algiers

Jan 2020 — Jun 2020

I have built multiple deep learning and machine learning models in the project "Sentiment Analysis Algerian Dialect". I went through different steps, let me resume them for you.

- · Data Collection from Facebook
- Having done deep research of related works then I have invented my own solution by contributing to the subject of 'Sentiment Analysis Arabic Dialect'
- · Data cleaning
- Implementing common models of deep learning and machine learning then proposing my own model by combining different models, then comparing different architecture

Resolution of communication problem between two applications using Web Service, General Directorate of Douane

Algiers

Jan 2018 — Jun 2018

I have created a web service that automatically allows data exchange between two websites using Java, MySQL, and Bootstrap.

Participation in Chatbot system, Emplorium

Aug 2021 — Dec 2021

I have participated in a chatbot website that allows communication with customers.

- · Creation of multiples agents accounts.
- · A customer can ask any question in the chat.
- Each agent can answer customers' questions. So agents between them work at the same time without any problem.

Participation in Scholar management system, Lakkini

COURSES

ReactJs, Zero to Hero academy

Deep Learnin in NLP, Coursera

Machine Learning, Coursera